# **BRADLEY MUA**

4505 Clermont Dr., Northeast, DC 20011 Home: 2407791566 | Cell: 2024607049 Bradthe50@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Proactive and seasoned technical writer/Developer with five years' experience working with top executives in fast paced Financial Institutes and Firms. Superior computer skills and telephone etiquette. Driven and focused with proven excellence in written and oral communication and presentations. Resourceful and independent problem-solver. Manage multiple schedules and maintain communication across teams. Focused, consistent, punctual, and reliable. Organized and trustworthy with confidential and personal information.

## **SKILLS**

- MS Office Suite: Word, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint; Paint
- Creative problem solver and trusted keyholder
- Versed in SnagIt Screen Capture and Camtasia
- MS Windows 8/Windows 10/Apple iOS 13/iOS 14 expert
- Quick books Pro and Quick Books Premier proficient
- Madcap Flare Professional
- Schematics, drawings, and technical documentation expert versed in API Documentation tools likes Swagger and Active campaign
- Experienced in Software Testing
- Editing reporting of up to 250 pages and slide presentations of up to 50 slides
- Great verbal and written communication skills
- Years of Experience dealing with JSON, Madcap Flare, Adobe FrameMaker, XML, Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Visio, Google Docs/Drive, Acrobat, SharePoint, Citrix.
- Knowledge of scripting languages such as JavaScript, PYTHON
- Exceptional command of the English language, especially in AP or MLA writing style
- Versed in WordPress, MySQL, Visual Basic, Bootstrap and GitHub
- Display High level of confidentiality in all business matters.
- Proficient with CRM System and as well as cloud-based systems (Google Drive, Apple Suite, and more)

### **WORK HISTORY**

# Technical Writer First Republic

February 2021 to October 2021

Promote, shepherd, develop, and maintain high quality documentation that meets applicable standards and is appropriate for its intended audience.

- Worked with internal teams and subject-matter experts to obtain an in-depth understanding of applications/systems/ processes/products and ensure the information is accurately documented
- Work with JavaScript frameworks (ReactJS and AngularJS) to connect between our APIs and our front-end web interfaces
- Created enterprise JavaScript solutions to be delivered at run time to host pages and executed in a SaaS manner
- Demonstrated knowledge of Bank standards and processes

- Managed expense processing through Oracle, reimbursed and accounted for reconciliations.
- Conducted SharePoint inputs with our quarterly/semi quarterly RCSA testing results.
- Worked with UX specialists to make interfaces appealing, easy, attractive, and simple
- Participated in product specifications through rapid iterative prototyping and UI simulations in code with live data
- Create Infrastructure Disaster Recovery Procedures.

# Strategic Content Writer E. Cohen and Company, CPAs

#### November 2019 to December 2020

Produced variety of content including internal/external business communications, informative articles, proposal content, creative marketing, blog, and social media posts

- Revamped Excel Record-Keeping and reported to furnishing executives with more accurate financial data.
- Oversaw the development of high quality, high impact artwork and graphics for proposals
- Met proposal deadlines by establishing priorities and targeting dates for information gathering, writing, review, and approval.
- Conducted research, including reading source materials, using the application software, and meeting with and interviewing subject matter experts (SMEs)
- Determined proposal concept by identifying and clarifying opportunities and needs, studying requests for proposal (RFPs).
- Defined strategy and guidelines for the Salesforce technical landscape (CRM and other solutions on Salesforce)
- Facilitated meetings with SMEs to develop content for RFP
- Experience in providing account management services with cloud-based/SaaS solution offerings
- Designed and developed integrations between Salesforce and other applications / systems.
- Built and maintained the content/proposal repositories maintaining quality and document version control
- Wrote to technical/management volumes, cost narratives, past performance, and resume requirements

#### **Technical Writer 1**

#### May 2018 to August 2019

#### Guzman & Griffin Technologies Inc

Collaborated with SMEs during design phase to gain understanding of products and during development stages to ensure technical accuracy and completeness of help.

- Tested Software against help content, reported software bugs, and submitted change requests and user interface (UI) recommendations to software developers.
- Using Flash MX. Developed interactive materials for deployment on carrier websites.
- Maintained an accurate record of financial transactions using Xero, Salesforce, and QuickBooks

- Prepared and maintained online documentation of test software for products including context sensitive and HTML based help files.
- Created and maintained documentation web pages using Git/GitHub, Markdown and Umbraco.
- Provided proofreading for marketing collateral.
- Converted documentation to DxStudio and Markdown Formats.
- Created training material curriculum and course outlines.
- Wrote getting started tutorials, Help Drawer and MSDN content for Azure virtual networking and automation.

# **Editor/Content Writer**

January 2017 to January 2018

#### **Edge Floral Event Designers**

Principal technical editor for every public-facing news article posted on website over a year period.

- Produced Marketing materials for product release.
- Managed several documentations and training projects for various clients.
- Created screen mockups and incorporated them as clickables examples.
- Developed online help for enterprise content management (ECM)
- Designed and implemented complete overhaul of website to facilitate access.
- Performed upgrades to the virtual machine used to run the software and copied the new snapshot for distribution to authors when new builds became available.
- Recorded financial transactions and complete the posting process in QuickBooks Online for multiple clients.
- Developed guidelines to meet APA and MLA requirements for web interfaces.
- Developed a writing style guide, assisted with writing marketing materials, and provided input to corporate identity and branding.
- Prepared management reports including corporate Balanced Scorecard, PL Balanced Scorecards, Gross Margin and Budget reports.

### Digital Writer/Producer/Editor The Mendoza Law Firm

October 2015 to December 2017

Proofread news stories, special reports, and commentary and checked citations and links for accuracy

- Performed proofreading and light copy editing on in-house materials such as shells, summaries, news stories, special reports, etc. Checked for grammar, punctuation, clarity, style, and flow, ensuring conformity of format and style throughout.
- Edited, designs, and produced a section of the print issue highlighting new products, such as tools, equipment, and other products related to electrical construction.
- Ensured accuracy, completeness, and adherence to established formats following the company style manual and AP style.
- Wrote original copies when needed for news stories; adapted press releases into web-exclusive or newsletter content.

- Adept at creating high-energy promos and teasers for the company's app and various platforms
- Produced and edited videos with motion graphics and dynamic video effects for social media, digital platforms, and online videos for sports, entertainment, and news.
- Worked on various salesforce standard objects like accounts contacts opportunities and different custom objects.
- Copied/Edited editorial content, such as news articles, columns, and feature stories, for both print and digital platforms.
- Designed solutions by customizing various standard objects on salesforce

# **EDUCATION**

James Hubert Blake High School 300 Norwood Rd, Silver Spring, MD 20905 High School Diploma: 2014

**Howard University** 2400 Sixth St NW, Washington, DC 20059 **Associate of Accounting**  **Currently Attending** 

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

#### My References:

Sylvia Ebong (Senior Executive Assistant at E. Cohen and Company, CPAs) – 2023168662

Marquita McCullum (CFO The Mendoza Law Firm) – 2025779007

Scholastic Lawson (Edge Floral Events Designers) - 2405019375